the meeting starts. So, just give it a
moment for everybody to in the lobby to
actually be into the meeting.
>> Good afternoon everybody. This is
Dominic Zerlo with the Department of
Health and I am just here uh and our our
team from Department of Health is here
to administratively help with this
committee. We have some people who are
still coming into the meeting from the
lobby. So, we'll give them just a minute
um uh to join in. Uh and it looks like
everybody is in. So, at this point, I'll
turn it on over to you, Ian. Uh and Ian
Dunn is our chair. So, Ian, take it
away.
>> Hi. Good uh well, not good morning
anymore, but good e good afternoon
everyone. H I hope everyone is doing
well. This is the dosage administration
and clinical practice committee. Thank
you all for taking the time to be here.
I really do appreciate it. Um, hey
Dominic, if you are willing to pull up
the presentation for me.
>> Yes, I am doing that right now. It is
should be on in just a moment.
Uh, you should be able to see it now.
Well,
>> yes.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Um, again, welcome. This is
the dosage administration and clinical
practice committee. Today's objectives
are to review and adopt our definitions
of our dosage levels and uh just dosage
definitions in general that will be
relevant to this committee. Uh if you
can go ahead and go to the next slide.
So just as a quick reminder in case um
anyone has forgotten or anyone is new uh
committees operate in an advisory
capacity to the medical psilocybin
advisory board. Committee support the
board by expanding community input,
incorporating subject matter expertise,
and increasing participation in program
development.
All right, if you want to go to the next
slide.
Perfect. Um, so again, we will do
introductions. So if you wish to serve
and participate on the committee today,
please share your name, role, or area of
expertise and perspective or interest
related to dosage administration and
clinical practice. I'll go ahead and
turn it over to Hortte to unmute.
So, if you would like to speak and
introduce yourself, please uh raise your
hand.
Right.
Scott, your mic has been enabled. Please
speak when you are ready.
Hello everybody. My name is Scott
Fulkman. I am a professor of chemistry
at New Mexico State University. Um my
area of expertise is in analytical
chemistry and uh analysis in terms of
potency and impurities.
>> Thank you, Scott.
>> Please forgive me if I mispronounce your
name. You can correct me. Uh Laura, your
mic has been enabled. Please unmute
yourself when you're ready to speak.
I got it. [laughter]
Hi. Hi. My name is Laura Maruchi and I
am a New Mexico State certified peer
support worker. Um I 100% believe in
this program and I just want to be um
involved with everything that's going on
with it. Um I have started just started
a um LLC fighting for serenity and a
nonprofit called the Monarchs and um I
would love to have this program in my
programs. So I'm just I'm right here
just to listen. So that's here I am.
Thank you very much.
Hey, your mic has been enabled. Unmute
yourself when you're ready to speak.
Hi, my name is Chris Piski. My name is
Chris Piscus. I'm a ambassador for the
>> and I'm and I'm on the advisory board
and I'm just here to help out today.
Thanks.
Thank you, Chris.
Brenda, your m Oh, sorry. Give me one
second. Brenda, go ahead. your your mic
is enabled. Please introduce yourself
when you're ready.
>> Hello everyone. Um my name is Brenda
Burgard and I'm on the advisory board
for the medical psilocybin
um member and I am in charge of and
chairing uh the education and training.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. Lawrence, your mic isn't
enable is enabled. Please unmute
yourself when you're ready.
>> This is Larry Leman. um a member of the
advisory board as well. My um area of
expertise is research with psilocybin
mushrooms and I'm on the call to share
perspectives regarding issues of dosage.
>> Thank you Larry.
James your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready to
speak.
>> Thank you sir. Uh my name is James Brown
of Doctor of Pharmacy. have been trained
in psilocybin use um in Oregon through a
program called uh Emerald Valley
Institute. Um I'm here today as a
educator as well as uh you know experts
in dosing administration uh
pharmaccoinetics dynamics all that good
stuff with pharmacy. Um it's a pleasure
to be here. Um thank you so much.
>> Thank you
Vincent. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself when you're ready
to speak.
>> Yeah, thank you. Uh my name is Vince
Espinosa. Uh I'm actually an LCSW. So
I'm licensed in Colorado, Oregon uh and
New Mexico. I'm actually uh pursuing uh
Colorado facilitator license uh for
natural medicine. I'm in a program with
Fluence Training uh to get a certificate
in psilocybin facilitation. So, I'm on
my third out of four classes and I will
get my training license here in May to
uh start uh my practicum in Colorado.
So, I'm here um as a practitioner and a
community member. Uh I was born and
raised in New Mexico and so I have a
strong interest in bringing this uh
lovely medicine to our community and
have witnessed firsthand how healing it
can be. So yeah, I'm excited to take
part in uh this committee in any way
that I can.
>> Thank you, Vince.
Eileen, your mute your your microphone
has been enabled. Please unmute yourself
when you're ready to speak.
>> Hi, my name's Ailen Brewer and
unfortunately I'm sick. I'm losing my
voice. So I hope you all can hear me.
Okay.
>> Yes.
>> Okay, perfect. Um so I am a researcher
and I am a patient advocate. I mostly
work with people who live with pain
conditions specifically headache
diseases but also other pain conditions
and I am excited to work with this
community and hope that I can represent.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you Eileen and wish you better
health.
Dan your mic is ena is enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready to
speak.
Hi everybody. I'm Dan Jennings. I'm uh
on the board as well and I'm the uh
chair of the uh research and continuous
improvement committee and I'm just here
to be part of this uh discussion as well
on dosage.
>> Thank you, Dan. Kate, your mic has been
enabled. Please unmute yourself when
you're ready to speak.
Kate Hawk, your mic is enabled. Is
enabled.
>> Yeah, it was it was actually disabled.
Now it now it's good. Thank you
everybody. Good to good to see you. This
is Kate Hawk from Santa Fe and I've been
involved with several committees
especially end of life care but what's
relevant u today is probably um involved
with Scottsdale Research Institute and
Sue Sisley in Arizona. I lived in
Arizona. I've worked with her for
several years and I'm I'm currently
involved with their work with uh they
have a federal license for psilocybin
mushrooms. So glad to be here.
>> Thank you Kate.
Gregory, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself when you're ready
to speak.
Sorry, multitasking and couldn't find
the screen.
Um, hi. Uh, my name is Gregory Evans. I
am an independent researcher. I live in
Santa Fe. Um I've been compiling
research around analytics,
genomics, [clears throat]
phlogenomics,
uh dosage and um how those dosages can
be targeted towards specific therapies.
Um [clears throat] Ian, I read your
paper. Um, [clears throat and cough]
I think that you did an incredible job
and I wanted to point out that like it's
funny because a lot of the stuff that
you wrote I can tell you wrote because I
know that it doesn't exist and I've been
writing the same stuff. So, um, I can't
wait to get into it and uh, find all the
parallels and find the next current
version of truth.
>> Thank you, Gregory.
And that's all the hands. Let me just go
through the chat. There is one person.
Uh my name is Ellen Shimz. I'm a
psychiatric nurse practitioner and Army
veteran. I've been a mental health nurse
for 28 years trained in psychedelic
assistant therapy through integrative uh
psych psychiatry institute. I'm also an
educator. Happy to share my expertise as
needed. Thank you. And Dominic has added
some uh instructions in case you would
like to speak. That's also on the screen
in front of you. So, whichever is best
for you. And those are there's one more
comment. Yeah, we came in. Uh, my name
is Matthew Armstrong, Ojiway descended
and psilocybin advocate. I do not have a
medical record. Happy to serve though.
And that's everyone. Ian,
perfect. Thank you. Um, if you can go
ahead and go to the next slide, it will
open the draft document that was sent
out to everyone so that we can open
discussion.
And I'm just going to open it in a
little bit of a different way. It
doesn't show if I try to click on it and
open it here. So, I'll have that in just
a moment. And just for those who are
wondering, uh, as we go through
sections, I will be putting those into
the chat as well. So, just uh give me
just a moment here.
Here we go. And can you see the screen
at this time? Should be able to see the
document.
>> Yes. So um I'm going to go ahead and go
briefly go through this that way we can
kind of catch up and get where we are.
So the psilocybin dosage definitions
begins with something known as maximum
theoretical psilicin. This is basically
the amount of psilicin the active
ingredient in magic mushrooms that is a
systemically available to our bodies.
Now I do want to note this measurement
is using a stokometric conversion. That
means that sometimes what happens in
chemistry labs is not exactly what
happens in our bodies and that's okay
but we are going to use what we have the
most evidence on and that of course is
going to be our stochometry until we can
collect more through this program and
through efficacy. So the MTP calculation
is just measured amount of psilocin plus
the measured amount of psilocybin with a
stochometric conversion factor that
allows us to um see the maximum
potential amount of psilicin that we are
going to be dosing someone. It allows us
to have one consistent unit of hey we're
going to prescribe this amount or this
range. Here's what we are listing within
the range because we have two
pharmacocinetically different molecules
that we are working with within the
mushroom itself.
So going into that further we then have
something known as an available silicin
fraction. So this describes the amount
of psilicin relative to the total
measure of millig of psilicin
equivalent. So it is our milligs of
psilicin over mtp
that's going to give us a percentage of
pure psilicin active psilicin that
already exists.
So some things we know about the
pharmacocinetics of psilicin um there's
not a whole lot of data but we do have
um an understanding that it is much
faster because it doesn't have to go
through the bio conversion into an
active molecule. So what we use this APF
for is to say what percentage is silicin
and that way when our facilitators are
going to be administering this drug they
can say hey
we know this has x amount of faster
acting
medicine and we have y amount of slower
acting. that will allow us to not
exactly predict but it will give us a
frame of reference for the medications
that we are providing to these patients.
So a higher APF greater proportions of
immediately available psilicin are
associated with higher likelihood of
early onset and more prominent early
psychoactive effects. Lower APF
indicates a greater proportion of
psilocybin requiring metabolic
conversion and are associated with a
higher likelihood of delayed onset and
extended duration. So we are going to be
trying to provide as much information to
our facilitators as possible in order to
ensure that they can do their job
correctly. So the next thing we go over
and this is the most provisional part is
something known as onset profile
categories.
So these onset profile categories each
is just a measure of how they how much
the percentage of active psilicin
impacts the onset of action. So we know
that psilicin has a faster onset of
action. We don't have specific numbers
on that yet. There isn't extensive
research on the pharmacocinetic
differences between psilocin and
psilocybin. Therefore, these
recommendations are provisional.
We recommend they're used for clinical
planning and monitoring. They are not
determinative classifications and
thresholds should be visited as outcome
data accumulates. So you'll see later
that we forward a lot of this to the
continue um research and continuous
improvement arm because I do believe
that there is certain evidence that we
don't have a lot of at the moment like
the effects of psilicin how psilocin and
psilocybin produce different systemic
effects.
The ne next thing that we have are just
dosage levels. This would allow us to
provide a recommendation. So if a
practitioner is going to provide a
recommendation, they can say okay I want
you to have a subperceptual dose for
let's say to as an onboarding ramp right
we know patients with PTSD are have may
have a higher incidence of what are
known as bad trips. Therefore a sub
perceptual dose would allow them to kind
of see the lay of the land before we go
ahead and give them a therapeutic dose.
um it's not meant to be something that
is you know totally provided. There is
not enough evidence at this time to
meaningfully say that this is safe and
effective and this will work for these
conditions. But it is it can be used as
an onboarding ramp. So I didn't want to
dis disincinlude it entirely.
A perceptual dose is a dose that is
expected to produce noticeable
perceptual, emotional or cognitive
effects. So we have three tiers of this
um or two tiers sorry we have a mild
perceptual which is basically above a
subperceptual dose but below 1 g of
mushrooms in equivalent so 10 millig of
MTP.
We have a therapeutic perceptual which
is going to go from 10 to 30. And then
we have later a high dose which is going
to give us a the ability to re recommend
these higher doses that we don't have as
much you know evidence behind for
certain people. Maybe they had a
previous experience. Maybe they are on
medications that are going to blunt the
effects of psilocybin. And so this gives
practitioners an avenue out to say okay
we understand that everyone has
different circumstances and we are going
to ensure that we are not blocking
anyone via overly stringent dosage
regulations. I will now open the floor
to any um discussion that people have.
What questions what things can we
change? This is a first draft so I want
to see what the committee thinks.
>> Chris
first in line. may begin.
>> So, I'm not sure I agree with using
total psilocin
content. I I think a better
um standard dosing might be total
equivalents psilocybin. I think this is
going to create a lot of confusion for
people. Um
and so that that's like the first
comment I got on that. Um, second is as
we're going down and looking at the the
subperceptual doses, I think most people
that micro dose actually perceive
perception changes. And so I don't like
that terminology. [clears throat] I
think subh hallucinogenic
might be
a better terminology in that regard. Um,
but those are the first couple things
that stick out to me.
>> Thank you, Chris. Larry, you are next to
the line.
>> Yeah, thank you. And thank you, Ian, for
for the document here. Um I I don't I
think we're getting ahead of the
evidence in the science here. And um
I've not seen the APF used in any
articles, any um I we actually obtain um
psilocybin um from the Scottsdale
Research Institute. It's approved by the
FDA. Uh they're not doing these type of
calculations. My own research is that
the um the psilocin can be highly
variable um based on which flush you
have, environmental conditions. Um the
actual absorption um um can also be
varied by the diet and different things.
And I I just think we're getting ahead
of the information and I would propose
not to include the APF. I'm also
concerned that we're maybe producing um
an undue burden on the uh on the growers
if they're going to need to, you know,
recheck every flush. So, that would be
my concerns about the APF. The sub
perceptual dosing is a challenging area.
There's almost no evidence really
regarding um regarding the role. It's
it's quite common in the uh community
and what roles are there and I I'm not
sure there's a reason for us to get into
making um uh making uh definitionitions
and actually suggesting which type of
product should be used for something
that we don't have any evidence for its
benefit or or lack of benefits. So I I
just feel like in both of these areas
we're getting ahead of the evidence and
it would be best not to include include
>> Thank you. Um I do want to challenge
back on the APF. Most FDA approved
studies are only going to use synthetic
psilocybin. Therefore they would not be
working with the biomass that we are
currently working with as a program. In
that sense we have to take differential
actions from what the FDA is doing.
Since we are a program that is allowing
the natural medicine, we specifically
exclude synthetic psilocybin and
psilocin. We have to take into
consideration the fact that these plants
or these fungi are going to grow with
[snorts] psilocin and psilocybin and we
need to be able to inform the patients
and the facilitators what percentage of
what is are they being provided.
Anyway, um, in regards to that, that was
my only response. That that's the clear
differentiation between a lot of the
studies and a lot of what we have here.
And so, I did want to clarify on that
point. I will go ahead and turn back to
more public comment.
>> Thank you both.
Gregory, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself when you're
ready. Would you believe that I've
already written up a response and have
an entire document to submit that I've
like just finishing now and I don't have
time to get it in and it's going to be a
whole thing. But I think this
conversation will be great. I want to be
super clear. I could talk for about 20
minutes in response to this and I want
to be respectful and constrain that. Um,
[clears throat] so yeah, I just wanted
to get consent to begin.
there before I because I don't want to
have like five things to address and
didn't want to like
speak over everybody.
>> So, so Greg, are you asking that you
want 20 minutes? Is that what you're
trying to say? I I would say if you
could limit what you have just so that
we can you know do this and remember
this is a a beginning as Ian said this
is a very rough draft we're going to
have many more conversations on this so
what I would say is uh if you can limit
it to five minutes as we've kind of oh
I'm sorry did we say three minutes on uh
in the committees my apologies I forget
off the top of
>> five for the committees because there is
a smaller population
>> gotcha I couldn't remember if we went
three and five or which way. My
apologies. So, Greg, if you could just
limit it to five minutes, that would be
great just to make sure we hear
everybody. And uh so I would say pick
your most important aspects. But thank
you for asking.
>> Yeah, in that in that understanding, um
is there potential for me to screen
share?
>> Uh I do not have a way to turn that over
to you uh at this point. So yeah, but
you can as always you can send the
documents with context afterwards and we
can put it in the meeting record.
>> Yeah. Um I think I can actually there's
a graph I want to present to. There's a
chart and a and a graph and I can
publish those and provide a link and put
that in the chat if it's okay. Um I'll
do that after I speak.
>> That would [clears throat] be fine.
>> Okay. So um I have an assumption of
where you extracted the the acronyms
from. Um probably the total potential
solosin
from Oregon's 333064
uh 0150
section 50. Um I have a recommendation
[clears throat]
that we shift away from using the term
theoretical and move towards potential
solosin. I think it's more accurate and
it gives us the ability to aim to a
target. So the construct that I would
like to present is uh the acronym would
be PCN
and this
stands for
uh solosin normalization equivalency
and so that directly
works with total psilocybin. So I put
the psilocybin equivalency of that and
call that PBCE
and those can be easily calculated from
one to the other. I am on the side of
the fence arguing that we should go as
for labeling. So testing getting the
analytics and labeling we have an
opportunity to push this to a medical
market and shift the perspective to
understand that we should be measuring
solosin equivalency.
Um several companies that do analytics
already utilize the concept of solosen
normalization.
Uh trtoics
um light labs
I don't know we'll ask whoever else is
in the room from the analytics
community.
Um
moving on key target dosage ranges micro
dose should be 0.1 to4 milligrams. This
is a subperceptual no acute effects. I
have what I call a calibration dose that
is.5 to 1.5 mg solosin equivalents. So
all of these measurements are in PCN
[snorts] solosin equivalent
normalization.
The calibration range is kind of what
you're looking for when you have this
like finding the threshold in a
non-threatening manner. This is a
technique that I think could be really
useful for people in the future. I also
don't want to get into what what Larry
was talking about like over specifying
this and making recommendations to the
way people should
uh present their therapy like I want to
keep it into clinical definitions right
so moving on we have threshold at 1.5
milligrams that is your first perceptual
dose there is a range that that shifts
but that is like the average Target a
mini dose which colloquial would be
colloial we would be your museum dose
that's 2 to 4 milligrams
you feel it in your body mild perceptual
shift pre- therapeutic that is your 3 to
7 milligram range
>> [__]
trans that is the transition between
non-therrapeutic to therapeutic
therapeutic range is 7 to 18 milligrams
solosin equivalency that 18 mg solosin
equivalency is your 25 mg psilocybin
equivalent.
>> Greg, you have 30 seconds.
>> Um, that is about it. I have a whole
conversation about the o the uh the
interaction between solosin and
psilocybin. I think we should probably
take that out for now um and reframe
some of that.
I yield.
>> Thank you. And I always read the public
comments after every meeting. So, please
feel free to submit it to the the
medical.silocybin
at what is it? Uh, Dominic.
>> Uh, it's medical.silocybin
[clears throat] duh.nm.gov.
And I will be putting how to submit
written public comments in the chat
momentarily.
>> Yeah, I do appreciate um all of the work
that you have looked into this. Um, and
then we can go ahead and move on to the
next speaker. Thank you,
>> Eileen. Your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself when you're ready
to speak.
>> Thank you. Um, I just wanted to uh
respond to the gentleman who said that
he was unsure if we should be addressing
lower doses and micro doses because the
evidence isn't there. While I recognize
that the initial targets for this bill
are not pain care um and that may be out
outside of the scope of the medical roll
out initially um I do know that the one
of the main goals is to allow for end of
life care and end of life care includes
pain care. What we know right now about
pain care with psilocybin is that it
includes
smaller doses
more frequently administered than would
be for say depression or anxiety or
PTSD. Um, and because we know this, I
think that it's important to continue to
consider those lower doses and how they
can be included without saying how often
they should be administered because I
think that's really up to the
practitioner and the patient that's in
front of them. Um, I also think that we
might want to consider a different word
than therapeutic for the perceptual
doses because therapy can come for many
different conditions in many different
ways and at many different doses.
Thanks.
>> Thank you,
>> Eric. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready to
speak.
Hello. Uh just wanted to say that uh
just for some of the people that are,
you know, wanting to not have the um the
regulation or the guidelines stating how
uh on dosage, um I would say that the
reason we need this uh laid out is
because things get lost in translation.
Not everybody's going to be growing the
same strains or fruit bodies in potency.
Uh if you are, you know, uh able to
acquire genetics for a certain species
or for mushroom for a certain, you know,
cultivar, um and you're running that in
your facility, uh it doesn't mean that
the next facility is going to be running
that same uh strain or species. And for
the, you know, uneducated,
uh, individual out there, um, they, you
know, would be under the impression
they're going to be having, you know, a
certain experience with a certain amount
of one. And if if and if they're under
the impression that it's equal across
the board, then, uh, there's going to be
issues with that. Um, and also some of
these dosages that I'm seeing in the um
document, uh, I don't know if anyone
here has personally experienced a uh,
you know, a
a 1 millgram dose of salosin or even,
you know, uh, you know, up to three. I
think it was 1.5 that it said in there.
That's quite a strong dose. So that um I
currently have you know um experience
with 3 milligram gummies that is pure
salosin extract or um you know or the
psilocybin equivalent and those are
above you know social experience um uh
basically like the you can't drive you
can't do things like that. So even that
metric of measurement is quite high uh
in my opinion. Um and uh so it's kind we
do lose things we do lose the mean
things get lost in translation when we
start going into these specific uh
measurements and uh I just wanted to
give that input and uh if anyone you
know has experience with with the um
salosin extract um they could probably
add to that. So just so you know just
just salosin as a measurement the
there's other uh alkyoids that cause
different things and so with a I got a
guideline of salosin measurement um we
are you know we're we're kind of missing
some of these um these properties that
are going to have an effect on the
experience. So
that's all. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
James, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready to
speak.
Thank you everyone. Um, I think you guys
hit a key point earlier. This is initial
discussions. I think we need to keep
that in mind as we go through this. Um,
you know, Ian, you've done a great job
at just presenting something to us. I do
appreciate that. Um I'm I'm on the side
of Larry's fence. Um listening to him
today, um I want to just echo the same
same similar things. I don't want to
have to repeat it, but I just definitely
want to say echoing at Larry's. I think
this complicates things and I know we
have a year to do this and I just want
to make sure we we make this easy enough
for people, but there's enough
information here that's very important.
I am in agreeance on the milligrams. Um
I think that's a standard that we've
seen across the board in the literature.
um this discussion between salosin and
psilocybin is very important. I think
that also involves a lot of the enzyatic
processes that are they're due to that
change unless we're just giving them the
pure solosin conversion and then again
if you do give somebody pure solosin um
you have that quick onset and shorter
duration. So we got to look at that
stuff when we're talking like this Ian
and group. Um, but great start. Um, I I
do have some differences on the dosings
of course, but I think as we get through
that, I think that will be maybe a
little bit of tweaking, um, stuff like
that. And then the wording, um, I'm glad
somebody brought that up, too. I just
didn't know if that therapeutic word was
something I had caught too. I don't know
if we want to use that, but it is the
medicine. So, therapy does make sense on
that word. Um,
and
I think that it's important that we also
sit here when we do look at these type
of proposals like this. Um, and look at
the individual. When we're thinking
about this, we need to think
individually. Not everyone's going to
have the same experience. Not
everybody's going to break down the same
way. Not everybody's going to do this.
And so, there needs to be I don't I'm
not saying flexibility, but just thought
process behind our decision-making at
the finals is that I just want to make
sure everybody's aware of that.
consciousness of this is individuals
here, you know, and it's sometimes there
needs to be a little flex or thought
about that. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, James. And and to kind of
agree with you, it it a lot of these
dosage ranges and I'm sure anyone that's
read the literature, they are all over
the place. They go from zero to 100. And
there is a it is often difficult to say
with certainty where the minimum
effective dose is or where the
therapeutic range is. So I am fully open
to changing those milligram proponents.
Something that I am concerned about is
losing the actual natural medicine
component of it.
we are working with two chemically
distinct molecules and so
it's very difficult to say hey um we're
just going to label this with the amount
of psilocybin that's in it and not the
amount of psilocin. So the most of what
this was to do was just to give us a
framework and an ability to collect more
data because right now there isn't
enough data on
how silicon is converted in the body.
There's a good amount of data on it from
a chemistry standpoint just not about a
biology standpoint. and we all have our
internal mechanisms and biology that is
going to contribute to how these things
play out. So I would be more than happy
to strike um the interpretation and
clinical significance of APF. But I do
think it's important to you know inform
our facilitators, hey you're giving
someone a very big dose of the
immediately active psilicin pursuant to
whatever strain that grew that way. Um,
and I think they should be, you know,
warned and said, "Hey, like this may
kick in faster. You may have a a shorter
duration of action. You may have some
other factors that are going to play
into this. This is going to what this
originally was meant to do was just to
say, "Hey, um, here's a way that we can
calculate the amount of
psychoactivity,
if you will, in this medicine because
ultimately there are two competing
chemicals in there." The reason why I
chose psilocin instead of psilocybin
for the basis of this dosage framework
um to answer some
that psilocin is the active one. It's
the one that's actually producing the
effects. And therefore, it is it makes
more sense to measure it in the active
ingredient, what it's going to turn
into, then try to imagine how to
backtrack a chemical reaction that has
already taken place and how much would
be there. Um, I just wanted to clarify
those points. For um the dosage ranges
though, I am more than open to changing
those, swapping them out, whatever um we
have to do cuz I am I have said this
from the beginning, there is a lot more
knowledge in the community in the state
of New Mexico than is in just my brain.
So whatever things we need change um we
can do. I'm really happy for this
discussion.
>> Thank you, Ian. We have uh comments in
the chat and two hands raised at the
moment and I will start with the chat.
Uh Shane McDaniel, will there be a
difference in potency within the same
cultivar for example golden teacher
between uh between different cultivators
depending on grow conditions and other
factors? Question mark. Kate Hawk, I
appreciate the recognition of the
complexities and nuances. I applaud
efforts to give maximum maximum
meaningful information while preserving
flexibility for appropriately dosing
people with unusual tolerance or other
conditions. Uh Gregory is respon has a
response to Shane McDaniel saying
potentially possibly likely this is a
great conversion for propagation.
And now we have a hand up unless you
wanted to answer any of those or uh
address those again. I mean no.
>> Okay. We'll go.
>> Yeah, I can kind of go ahead and it's
kind of like h in the medical cannabis
advisory board, they defined a unit of
THC being just 200 milligrams of or a
medical cannabis unit as 200 milligs of
THC. And so they did forget some of the
other chemicals. So I do recognize where
they are saying you know um alkyoids and
other um chemicals that can be part of
it. But in terms of what we have as
defensibly psychoactive and are the
usual culprits of what produces a
psychoactive experience. Um
that's what we're kind of working with.
I didn't set any type of here's one unit
equals this. I just said, "Hey, if we
took our psilocin that's in this
mushroom and we took the amount that we
could stochometrically get from
psilocybin,
then we would be able to have a dosage
definition that would work across
mushrooms even without, you know, um
without having to have
two dosage frameworks, one for
psilocybin and one for psilocin when
they're both growing in the same plant
or fungi. My mistake. Um I'll go ahead
and turn it again to public comment.
>> Thank you.
>> Adrian, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself when you're
ready. Speak.
>> Hi, thank you. Uh yeah, I'm Adrian, uh
owner of Druid's Choice. I'm currently a
cultivator in Colorado. Uh I just I do
want to comment real quick. Um on the
average doses that are being sold here
in co or utilized here in Colorado,
no one is really interested in micro
doing here uh mainly because the
regulations say that the patient has to
stay at the facility for two hours after
a micro dose. Now those of us that have
micro dosed personally, we know that you
don't need to stay there for two hours
to micro dose. That's the main reason
why they're not we're not micro doing
here. Um but there is a benefit in micro
doing um to for certain um conditions.
Um, number two,
um, uh, on the comment that Shane
McDaniel made, um, as far as difference
in potencies, there's huge difference in
potencies for the same. For example,
Golden Teacher, my current harvest is at
4.7 MTP.
Um, but I've seen some uh, from the
other cultivators as low as 3.2 3.5 MTP.
all golden teacher with uh the same u
alkyoid u background or the same present
alkaloids you know so to confirm that
they are all golden teacher
um and another thing on your APF I
that's not something we're doing here in
Colorado but I do know that you know
higher psilocin in the fruit is a
quicker onset and more body load um
higher psilocybin is a more extended
duration of the effects. Um
and then um the standard
dose here in Colorado has been about 30
milligrams. Uh I do sell mainly 30
milligrams with 5 milligram boosters or
10 milligram boosters to go to take that
30 to 35 or that 30 to 40. Um, when I
first started a few months ago, people
were requesting 20 milligrams, but um, I
guess, uh, everyone's averaging out to
higher between between 30 and 40 for
standard doses, and really nothing less
than that has been has been requested
from me specifically.
Um, and that's all my comment for now.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Chris, you are next in line.
>> You know, I I just wanted to say I
understand why you're going with you're
you're thinking we should go with
psilocin, but again, I think it's just
going to create a ton of confusion
because nobody most people don't know
what that is. They're going to be
looking for psilocybin content. People
have been knowing and engaging with this
plant as psilocybin for a long time. Uh
so I'll I'll make that case again to use
a different equation to look for total
equivalent equivalents psilocybin and
then
as far as the rest goes like quick onset
and everything there's so much patient
variability and people have different
sensitivities that dosage is going to
have to be highly individualized and and
and
regardless of whether you have you know
a large amount amount of psilicin
available immediately. Like somebody
could have an early onset.
Uh without that and
um from a facilitation standpoint, it
doesn't matter like you're you're there
to support them through that journey,
you know, regardless. So
thank you.
>> Thank you, Chris.
>> Thank you. But I do think it is
incredibly important that people can be
educated on what they're getting
themselves into. If someone if we're not
providing them the proper education on
what they are taking, then we can't have
meaningful informed consent. And the
reason that we're doing this again is
because it's a lot harder to say, okay,
how much
um psilocybin is from psilocin
than the other way around. We could
stoometrically reverse it but that
wouldn't be applicable to how the
conversion actually happens in the
in the world. Um but I am very concerned
with making sure that we can provide
proper informed consent to patients
because they need to know what is
happening in the body versus what is
just going to hit them with a quite
rapid onset.
I will go ahead and turn to Larry. He
had his hand up.
>> Correct.
>> Thank you, Ian. And just just one more
comments. Um and I agree with I totally
agree with you. You know, most almost
all the research has been with um
synthesized but but but we are actually
using the whole mushroom here and
working with um Dr. Sicily and what the
FDA has mandated is actually psilocybin
is what they're keeping track of and
that the psilocybin is needs to be plus
or minus 10% of what's um you being
described. I I think part of that may be
the difficulty of um measuring and
variations in each batch in different
flushes. So um I really hope that
whatever we develop is something that
won't be a burden to the to the
propagators and won't confuse the uh the
facilitators. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you so much. And I do appreciate
your comments because in all reality and
this may be an issue more for
propagation and manufacturing, but
silicon is a lot less chemically stable.
So even if how long are those testing
requirements going to last for and
things like that can also play a factor.
I am not going to claim that this that
that draft that I provided you guys was
perfect and you know needs no
correction. But I do say that it does
provide at least some framework that we
could hash out the details cuz I again I
don't know everything unfortunately. I
think it would be kind of cool but
[laughter]
um I do really appreciate everyone's
comments even the if you're feeling like
it's being contrarian or anything I just
this is inherently a process of saying
what is going to be best for the patient
and I appreciate all questioning from
anyone. I'll go ahead and turn it back.
>> Thank you, James. Your mic has been
enabled. Unmute yourself when you're
ready to speak.
>> Ian and everyone. Um,
I really like the idea of the solosen.
Um, and I like the idea of the
psilocybin because that's what's
currently being trained on and being
educated around. So, it would be a way
to include both
because we are setting new
you know, as they would say in Star
Trek, right? Like new frontiers, we're
doing that right now. And sometimes we
need to think outside the box and say
maybe we need both. Um, at the end of
the day, um, just a thought because we
can train on both. We can educate the
public on both. It's going to be clear.
We can really dial that up and say,
"Here's your product." It's kind of like
the cannabis and CBD. You get so much
THC, you get so much CBD. You're getting
so much psilocin, you're getting so much
psilocybin. Maybe you don't get any
psilocybin, you just get all silosin.
That'll be up to the therapy plan. And
that's my next point. Some of these
dosings are all going to be based off
these therapy plans for individuals,
based off of that relationship that's
created. And so, just wanted to think
about that, too, is we're going to back
into some of this stuff as we get the
therapy plans together. um for the
different you know ICD10 [snorts] um
wonderful things that we've done so far.
So that's all Ian um that's my comment
on that though. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Uh Dominic, you want to let
you go ahead in line if there are
something you want to address.
>> Sure. Thank you, Jorge. And just so
everybody knows, this is a great
conversation and I'm really glad it's
happening. Um just to kind of address uh
the issue and why it's so important to
have this now is um when we did create
the units with regard to cannabis. Part
of the issue it wasn't so much that it
was forgotten about the other aspects.
It's that the testing wasn't very
reliable yet to be able to actually
measure them very well. And so when the
unit was created and it was decided to
be based just on THC and not the other
potential uh you know uh items that
could affect that entourage effect, it
ended up being there. And so to change
it years later when the measurements
were going to be much more precise and
able to measure other forms and other
aspects CBD and everything else became
very difficult to do because the
industry standard had already been set
at the THC. So the compromise maze what
made was to ensure that things were
included on the label but that the
measurement with regard to units stayed
at the THC. And so I bring that up
because it highlights why this
conversation right now is so important
and why I can say it's not going to be
the last time we have that the
conversation because we have to make
sure that we are able to put this into
place in a way that it's going to um be
beneficial, not so restrictive, but also
that we could potentially change it down
the road as the research continues and
we find out the things we do not know at
all. right now. And so that's just one
of the things to think about is there we
know a fair amount of things regarding
psilocybin and salosin, but there are a
lot of things we do not yet know. So we
have to think about that when we look at
regulations and protocols and dosing. So
I'm just going to leave it at that. It's
just great conversation and I'm really
glad that it's happening. So thank you.
>> Thank you, Dominic.
and your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself and we're going to
speak.
>> Hi everyone. Um my name is Dr. Anne
Metsz and I'm um a licensed
um professional counselor and I am also
a natural medicine facilitator. I'm
licensed in Colorado but I live in TA.
Um, and I would just, um, ask for a
purely pragmatic reason to stick with
Salosen since that's what Colorado has
done. Um, I know that, you know, we're
we're doing a very different program,
but just for a sort of practicality for
facilitators, you know, the way I do
informed consent, the way I talk about
dosing um, in the non-directive model in
Colorado is insolic. And so from a
pragmatic standpoint, it would be lovely
to be able to continue to talk about it
that way in New Mexico. Um, and I
imagine that lots of facilitators will
be licensed in both states and so I
suspect I'm not the only person who
might bump up against that. But thanks
for all your work and great document,
Ian.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Shane. Your mic has been
enabled. Please unmute yourself when
you're ready to speak.
>> Yeah, I'm maybe in the minority here.
Um, and I'm but I'm going to take a
chance on it that I'm what I have to say
might be valid. Um,
the ancestral users of this medicine
have been using it for hundreds if not
thousands of years.
They do not dive into the weeds like
we're diving into here. I'm talking
about solosin and
grams and micrograms and solocybin and
you know um tryptophenes and everything
else we're talking about. I understand
the
this is new and we're trying to
um dot all our eyes and cross all our
tees, but we can get into this position
where we're in a paralysis by analysis
and we can't get anything done because
we are analyzing
things so far down into the weeds
[snorts]
that it becomes counterproductive.
when
you know if we're looking at patient
safety
um
from my understanding the harmful dose
or the lethal dose is so high that we
we'll never have anybody reach the
harmful or fatal dose or lethal dose.
Um, we might have some trial and error
periods with certain patients where, you
know, we might start off with too low of
a dose and and and then have to go up,
which means that patient is now is ex um
experienced double cost because they
have to go back for a a new dose that
they didn't get right on the first time.
I just think that, you know, like I
said, the the ancestral users of of this
at at most would measure it out in uh in
dried mushrooms. Um, not not in the
different chemical compounds or the
different strains or all that. And
again, I'm not saying that we shouldn't
pay attention to this. I just don't want
to get so deep in the weeds on this that
we forget or we get, you know, to like a
a point of paralysis by analysis, if
that makes sense. Thank you.
Thank you, Shane.
>> Denali, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself when you're ready
to speak.
Hi everyone. I'm um really appreciating
this dialogue. Um this is definitely not
anywhere close to an area where I have
expertise to offer, but I wanted to
offer a couple of process
recommendations or or questions. Um, I I
think it would be helpful for me at
least to hear maybe from the department
what the most important pieces of dosage
are for the program to be able to move
forward. Like what is the minimum
requirement for regulation
um that the department needs from the
department's perspective needs to be in
place for this to move forward. And then
I I would recommend sticking as closely
to what those minimum requirements are
just because it feels like the consensus
here is that we're we're learning so
much and and we will will as the program
enrolls um continue to learn. And so if
we can um if we can regulate as uh as
leanly as possible, it makes it a lot
easier to uh to to adapt and move
forward. Um, and I I just want to
recommend too, I know that there will be
more conversations. Um, I think it would
be especially valuable to have um the
input of the healthcare authority um
member on the advisory board um have
input here. I know I'm I'm joining from
the round house and I keep seeing them
around here too. So, I know they're very
busy with session. Um, but I hope that
we won't move forward without uh hearing
from them their input um from both a
patient safety perspective and what is
going to be possible for um coverage and
reimbursement and what what data points
they're going to require when we're
making dosing decisions. Uh they'll just
have some unique perspectives that I I
think need to be captured and and want
to be sure as a part of the the
drafting.
Thank you,
Ian. I just want to catch up uh on a few
things in the chat and then before we go
to the next hand, uh let's see where we
were.
Um [clears throat]
Gregory dropped a uh link in the chat as
far as propagation. Uh, and then Eric
says, "Yes, Gregory, I would agree with
more with your dosage recommended,
especially in the micro dose levels.1
milligram as opposed to 1 milligrams
pilent." Uh, much more practical. Um,
posed, uh, Gregory added, "Can we get
Barry Dunan or Scott Fulkman to weigh in
on the commality
of using silicon normalization in the in
the industry?" And then uh Eric says uh
there needs to be an improved universal
metric. I vote silicon as the most
comprehensive metrics silicon EQ is is
that metric. Uh Paul Walton, it would be
great to see a micro doing program maybe
a standalone program amongst others. Our
veterans and first responders are taking
pharmaceutical depression and anxiety
med medications. Micro doing can get
people off of uh these pharmaceutical
medications. Additionally, some veterans
on first responders are going back to
work and receiving even more trauma
where micro doing can help with some of
the negative side effects. Treating
micro doing as other medications that
allow people to be adults and take
responsibility for their medication
treatment and to not take more than
prescribed that would lead to
impairment. Thanks. Uh Laura added, "I
agree with Shane and Greg added in the
chat. The way I see authorizing micro
doing happening is an iterative one. If
we write the language now, but the
framework for where it could exist as we
roll out the program and collect data,
we will absolutely be able to collect
the data on potency analysis to help
build the effectiveness for safe use."
Uh, and now we have a couple of hands
up.
Greg, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready to
speak.
[clears throat]
Um, I wanted to kind of address some of
that stuff
about traditional use. Um
and I come from entering this space by
like counting mushrooms that I pick from
the ground. Um traditional use is
commonly
con traditional ancestral use is
um you know
you have I mean if you look at Sabina's
work it's like you send the kids to the
to the forest to collect a number of
mushrooms during a certain time of day
and they walk back and they avoid
certain omens and they bring these to
the house and then you distribute pairs
of certain types of mushrooms. Other
types of mushrooms you separate and
consider in different value of different
ways, right? And there's a comp
complicated spiritual framework for
this.
I don't want to take that away. I don't
think there's any
world in which the spirit and the
intuition behind dosage can go away.
Like when it comes to the end of the
day, like I'm the one that's counting
this the most in the room. [laughter]
Um but when it comes to me taking
mushrooms, I've listen to the mushroom,
right? What we're trying to do is create
a framework that will
influence the people in the seats of the
medical industry that we have done our
due diligence, that we understand what
we're recommending to people, what we're
asking people to do. We're asking people
to understand. So if I'm a facilitator
and I am a person that likes to do a
muscle test when I'm choosing a dosage
for my client,
I have an amount of mushrooms that I
know fits inside this box. But then the
process and the ritual of helping that
person be a part of that decision,
nobody's trying to take that away. This
is not about telling facilitators
how much to give somebody. This is about
understanding what the terms are,
how somebody in a lab somewhere can
understand something so that we can
really provide harm true harm reduction.
Because
if you don't understand how variable
mushrooms are can be and you don't know
what the variability is in that
mushroom, most of the facilitators
aren't going to be providing or growing
or testing their own mushrooms. It's
very important that they understand
that. I do think that the idea of
putting the um alkaloid ratios between
solosin and psilocybin on the package is
a good one. You can easily put PCB on
there right next to PCN or however you
want to acronym that. Put the solosin
and psilocybin. It's a simple math
equation. Um, and then one typo that I
found in your document Ian was the 30 mg
that you calculated from 25. You
calculated that the wrong way. It should
be 18
for the high dose.
But yeah, nobody's trying to take spirit
the spirit away.
At least I'm not.
>> Thank you. Um, yeah, and
in all fairness,
I do want to put point out that it is
one document, but it's really two
documents in the sense there's a
definitions and then there's a dosage
levels. So we can kind of separate those
two ideas because I think they are
not pointing toward the same thing.
Personally um I
am not a facilitator in Colorado like a
lot of you are. So seeing those numbers
that you guys see all the time is not
something that I do. So I really do
welcome all input from wherever you can
bring it because it is important that we
don't take the spirit away from this
medicine and it's also important that we
ensure that if we are going to put a
whenever a medical provider makes a
recommendation they're putting their
license on the line and so to make sure
that they are comfortable enough saying
here I recommend this is a really big
part because the legislation that was
passed requires there's a provider
authorization and so we need to make
sure that they can see this and not just
immediately
make it illegal by proxy because we
didn't set up a robust enough system
where we can ensure patient safety where
we can ensure that our dosage levels are
correct where we can show our data that
we are going to collect. So I think this
conversation is a really important one
and I do appreciate all comments. So I
believe I see James Brown with his hand
up.
James, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself if you're ready to
speak. Thank you, sir. Appreciate you.
Ian, just a thought too on as we get to
the different dosage levels or different
regimens
and the thought of split dose. So that
let's say the total dose there does need
to be any type of caveat or sentence
that says that that 30 can be split into
two.
they would receive the total 30, but you
know, it gives that safety profile a
little bit more buffer there if if
that's needed between the two. Make
sense? So, when you're there and you're
in that session with that person and if
if you feel like they changed or
something and their safety plan allows
that again, because we won't go back to
safety plans. If that safety plan allows
this, then you could split it. But that
has to be kind of written in this the
the original,
you know, therapeutic regimens. Um, I
just thought that I don't know what's
your thought on that. If we have some
type of terminology added says that the
higher doses may be split, but the
patient still would receive, you know,
based off the therapy, they might only
use half. I mean, it depends on what's
going on, you know, but I just wanted to
see if that was available as an option.
>> In my head, yes, it was. That was kind
of how I imagined it. Um, it's why there
are, you know, certain there's no
exclusion for how they have to be spread
apart. Um, I really wanted them to start
low and slow, right? Kind of like we
tell people for cannabis, low and slow
because if once we have a a bad
reaction, it's a lot harder to reverse
that bad reaction than if we oh, they're
starting to see paranoia. we can use our
therapeutic techniques and kind of
stabilize them down, but we're not going
to continue to up the dose of a medicine
that could be causing paranoia. So, I I
do believe that that would be a good
idea. Um, and then in future drafting,
we will include that. This is not the
again, this is not the final version.
This was something for y'all's brains to
digest and to say, I don't like that, or
I do like that part, or anything like
that. I really appreciate you guys.
Okay, we have a couple of comments in
the chat. Deb Thorne, functional
kinesiology equals muscle testing for a
substance. And Gregory Evans added, I
would like to loudly not put any
regulatory language on dictating max
dosage.
And
>> in the current dosage levels, there is
no regulatory maximum for dosage.
And then Eric Baka says, uh, maybe we
leave dosing to open and just come up
with guidelines for testing for known
tryptoamine content.
We have a hand up.
Greg, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready.
Yeah, feel free to cut me off if this is
out of scope for this conversation, but
um just [clears throat] experientially
experientially like through my journey
as I began cultivating and did not have
access to HLC or massspec data like or
even now that I do, I just don't have
the the money as an individual to send
off a chunk of what little I have.
um [clears throat]
when I do get data, it's really valuable
for me to walk it back against my
experiential data. But if you look at
the chart I posted, I have this little
calibration zone. And essentially what
I'll do when I get a new batch is I will
eat
a very little bit of it and then I will
eat a little bit more and then I will
eat a little bit more until I can just
feel it. That's like your the eyes start
to wake up, the tingling happens, the
early sensations just start to let it
let you know that it's there. That's how
I find my target for that species, that
cultivar, that batch of how much I want
to use for a micro dose or how much I
want to use for a macro dose. Each
person is going to find their
calibration a little bit differently. So
there's a range in there and it's like
flexes in and out of that. But there is
a very safe process of w of titrating
into a known first
interaction with the molecule.
Um
I don't think that that's something that
people necessarily need to do with every
patient. And if we understand that math
and then we can apply analytics to
sidestep some of that because like most
of our facilitators are doctors, they're
not going to be eating those mushrooms
for a week before they hand them to
somebody. Like they need to walk in
there with a known product that has been
just understood
and handed off. There's a lot of this
stuff that really belongs in the
propagation and analytics side of things
and we'll talk about that in 20 30
minutes or whenever that happens.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I mean I don't know if that's too much
for here but I mean yeah that's my
>> it is a good insight into
how dosage can vary. I think it it
almost mirrors the the entourage effect
a little bit in that different alkaloids
can provide that but a lot of that would
be for dosage and them. Uh the
department had a comment.
>> Oh, can I plug one thing before I have
to talk again?
>> Sure.
>> So like I want to test for all alkyoids
and develop I have this con concept of a
fingerprint. So every every culten
cultivar is going to have like a unique
effect, right? So we have to normalize
the PCN dosage to begin to understand
that. So the the alkyoid ratio between
solosin and psilocybin is only one
aspect and I think that's enough to put
on like the dosage kind of calendar. But
then everything outside of that, how
every part of that mushroom affects it
is like this fully underststudied
branch of research that like I am very
interested in and nowhere in the world,
nowhere in history have we had the
opportunity to get that information. Um,
I just think that we can and I look
forward to understanding these mushrooms
a little bit more.
So yeah, the the testing would
definitely be a conversation for the
dosage or for the propagation committee.
Um but in terms of testing for all
alkyoids, I wouldn't have a problem with
that. The reason I base the dosage as of
now on psilocybin and psilocin was that
those are the two alkyoids that are
specifically laid out in SP219
that the law that we're operating under.
So, I just went with that being that
that was the natural regulatory step was
to regulate those two substances
specifically. Um, but I will go ahead
and turn over to Dominic.
>> Yeah. And you're not wrong, but the
market will drive it.
>> Yeah. Thank you, Ian. And and I just
want to clarify something is I I think
some people have the misperception that
everything that we're talking about here
within this committee is going into the
regulations and Denali had that question
about what is needed by the department
with regard to the regulations. A lot of
this these ideas around the dosage and
the administration are going to be a
part of the protocols and the guidelines
not necessarily a part of the
regulations. There will be some aspects
that will be in regulation. For example,
what is going to be the definition of
you know how do we measure? So that is
definitely uh something that needs to be
discussed. But that does fit a little
more in with the propagation and
testing. But either way, most of what
we're talking about here within this
aspect is going to be a part of those
recommendations guidelines with regard
to it. And part of the reason for that
is as a few people have sort of noted in
the chat um we don't want to put an
actual dosage into the regulations
because again as the research comes out
and we're able to fine-tune things a
little bit and as individual patients
have different uh levels that are going
to be appropriate for them. We don't
want to hinder the process and that that
working together between the medical and
the therapeutic practitioner and the
patient. And so just remember those
aspects. A lot of what we're talking
about here are going to go into those
guidelines and protocols, not
necessarily into the regulations. So, I
just wanted to make sure that's clear so
that people know this is an ongoing and
evolving area of it and we're going to
do our best not to lock it in so that we
don't recreate as we mentioned before
that mistake of suddenly only having one
item, one aspect of it that is actually
creating problems and issues down the
road when we have more information in
two, three, five, 10 years. So, please
just do remember that. So, if you're
worried that, oh, we're suddenly going
to have all of these doses in the
regulations, that is not the intent.
Anyway, back to you, uh, Ian.
>> Yes. And, um, that's another reason that
I provided ranges is because what the a
lot of studies are using weight-based
calculations of dosages. There is some
controversy about whether that is
applicable with psilocybin. Um, but when
I provided the original dosage,
subperceptual dose of 2.5 mg, it wasn't
thinking of someone, you know, 90 lb
soaking wet with rain boots on. It was
someone that is, you know, maybe larger
or has more body mass. So that maybe it
takes more for them to get an un a
subperceptual dose. Uh while the
information is still evolving, we have
an obligation to collect data and to
ensure that we know what we are giving
patients. So I believe at least the
first part of this, the MTP and APF are
pretty solid in what they do. Um
and I haven't heard a whole lot of
objection. I've heard some about um the
APF, but can we all get an agreement
about MTP? Is that something we can all
agree on? I would love to hear your
comments on that, but I will turn back
to Jorge.
Okay, we do one have one hand up, but I
want to catch up here in the in the
chat.
Let's see. Eric, let's see. Trying to
find out where I left off. Here we go.
James Brown added, "I am in favor of
having both the psilocin and psilocybin
being reported for increase in analysis
and enhance public safety." Eric Baka
says, "Yet to be determined." Scott
Fulkman testing should probably be done
for psilocybin, psilocin, biocisty. Oh,
here we go. Norbocyin and arugus. Oops.
I'm not sure if I pronounced that
correctly, but here we go. That's in
[snorts] the minutes. uh they all have
different pharmaceutics and potencies.
Further research is needed for better
understanding of their independent and
entourage effects. But if the
concentration of each of these is known
and reported for each batch, they can
each be reported which prevents some
confusion with the definitions. Gregory
Evans says, "I would love to have access
to veagal tone measure and gut health
prior to and after dosage to define the
human elements of the equation." And
Kate adds, uh, more appreciation for
this sensible, well-informed process,
there are several lenses that we're
looking through scientific, therapeutic,
public perception. Lawmakers
observations from groups in Colorado
with the same batch of mushrooms. Some
participants with apparently similar
bodies had roughly half the effect on
twice the dose. And then James added, I
agree with MTP definition
of available psilocin fraction. add
definition of available psiloc
psilocybin fraction. I also agree on
excluding the others for entourage
effect if it's cost effective.
I can go back to uh raised hands here.
Shane, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself when you're ready to
speak.
>> Yeah, a couple of things. Um, we've
we've had a lot of talk on keeping price
down. The more requirements we have on
laboratory testing
and what we want them to test for, and
again, I go back to um I understand the
need to
be safe,
but are we being so safe that we're
making it so expensive that we're
pricing out the people that need it the
most? That is my biggest concern with
this folks is that we like Colorado and
like Oregon make this so complicated
that the people doing it have to charge
so much that we price out the people
that need it the most.
Um and and again,
you know, the the ancestral users of
this um
are where we should get most of our
information on dosing from. I believe
that wholeheartedly.
Secondly, I'm still seeing a lot of
comments about micro doing and I agree
100 to, you know, 150% that we should be
allowing u micro doing. However, just
like in Colorado that Adrian talked
about earlier and I had this
conversation with Dominic before we even
broke out into subcommittees, the way
the bill is written and we can only stay
within the guidelines of the way the
bill is written. Just like Colorado
though, if they're going to do any
dosing, it has to be done
at a clinic and they have to stay for a
certain amount of time, which
unfortunately
makes micro doing near impossible
because nobody's going to go in and stay
in a in a um facility for two hours
every day to do to do their micro doing.
Can we possibly in the future get a new
bill or a change to the bill to where we
can allow it? Yes. But let's work on
that after we get this program up and
running rather than because and Dominic,
please step in if I'm wrong. If we want
micro doing now
with this bill, would we not have to
send this bill back to have them rewrite
it
and send it back to us? [snorts]
>> Yeah, ju just to answer that Shane is so
with the law the way it currently is is
the dosing does have to happen at
approved locations. Now we are trying to
figure out some ways that that can be
done with regard to hospice in similar
situations. Uh because obviously you
cannot have somebody who is confined to
a bed or otherwise is not able to be
mobile to you know ask them to go to a
clinic even down the street from them.
And so we are trying to figure some of
that on out. But it does make it very
impractical
uh with regard to micro doing because of
the issues that they have seen in both
Oregon and Colorado. That doesn't mean
that it can't necessarily change down
the road, but for the very beginning uh
and Eric, I appreciate that about the
doctors for uh to approve the home.
There's a lot more than just saying we
approve the home. There are safety
issues that I know a lot of people would
say or may say, well, why do we have to
be worried about that, but there are all
it would take, for example, is one
caregiver running into an issue, getting
hurt that could potentially create
issues. So, we have to be a little
cautious with that because we want to
ensure the longevity of the program. So,
we want to do things the right way so
that it doesn't end up having a problem
to get shut down quickly and then us not
to be able to help anyone. So we need to
make sure that we're doing things in a
way that fit within the uh the structure
of the bill and also within safety so
that we can ensure there are not
problems that create it. Do I think
there are ways to do that? Yes. Will
that probably be a part of our initial
launch in December? Probably not. But
that doesn't mean we don't want those
conversations so that we can figure out
what those challenges, potential
obstacles are and figure out ways around
them. But to get things started, we need
to focus on, you know, how is this going
to happen within a clinic. Let's get
that part moving forward. And then we
can look at some of those other aspects.
uh especially as we see how the hospice
actually rolls out works and so that if
we have to pivot on anything we can do
so quickly without it being something
where we're taking things away from
people because that's the last thing we
want to do is start saying you can do
this and then we have to pull it back
because of potential issues or concerns.
So we have to make sure we look at that
all clearly and well so that it doesn't
become an issue or a problem. So the
conversation is good. We want to
overcome those challenges. We have to
figure out how to do that. Our first
step though is implementing the program
in a way that we can.
I hope that makes sense.
>> Yeah. And and like I said, I just don't
want I just want to make sure everybody
understands that um I don't think
anybody is disagreeing that we should be
doing micro doing. It's just that we're
not going to be able to do it under the
current way that the bill is written.
in this first go at this. Yes. Once
we're up and running or as we're getting
this up and running, we can include
facilities to include hospice care. It's
very doubtful that we're going to get
any approval on take-home micro doing
because nobody um uh the way it's
written, I don't think that the
approving body will ever approve that
we're calling people's homes a approved
facility.
Um we but we do need to work on that and
maybe in the next phase of this. I 100%
agree, but I just don't want to see a
lot of calories being spent continually
talking about this when it's just not
feasible in this first round of things.
Thank you, Shane.
That's all of our hands. I'll just catch
up on the chat. Um Eileen says, "I do
agree with giving practitioners a
jumping off point based on what we do
know. They can titrate up or down as
needed just like someone would do with
any other medication to treat the
patient. Like personally, I'm a
lightweight 0.5 grams of dried
psilocybensis
is is perceptual dose for me and I'm not
90 lb sucking wet. We know that it's not
based on weight in any cases. I do love
that there is great sensitivity for not
creating rules that will later need to
be changed as we learn more which is
often more difficult. We also don't know
if there are other compounds in
psilocybin containing mushrooms that
have therapeutic benefit because there
hasn't been a ton of research on it. We
might learn that in the future. Uh James
added, sorry, typo including them for
the entourage effect if most effective.
And um
see Eileen added also I know that the
group that is discussing practitioner
training is considering whether to allow
those who have already been trained in
programs designed for access in other
states. When we talk about what to use
for measurements we need to know how
others have already been trained if they
are to be included. If what New Mexico
outlines if different is different, it
might mean that additional training on
dose is required. And those are all the
comments and I don't see any hands up at
the moment.
>> Uh just one item [clears throat]
>> uh [snorts] Jorge and uh and for this
and Eileen, that's a great comment. I'm
glad that you brought it up. We actually
did already present briefly about the
fact that um uh if if there is
reciprocity because that's still a
question although I believe that that
will end up happening with regard to the
training that there will be a module um
that the department will actually create
that will have that information
regarding what New Mexico uh statutes
and uh procedures uh guidelines how they
differ from the other states. And so
that would be a requirement that they
would still be able to do or it's that
they would need to do uh to engage in
that reciprocity. So uh that that part
has already been done but exactly what
that includes we don't know yet and that
will be a part for that committee. So
thank you.
All righty. With no discussion I think
there is a few things that we were in
agreement on. So if we are good with MTP
and APF, um we might take a vote to just
approve those two. Then what I would
recommend after is
I'm going to say if you have a dosage
levels
schematic or framework that you would
like to submit, um you can submit that
to the email that Dominic provided that
medical.silicon doh.nm.gov. hub. Um I
will review them and you know compile
what the most common are as well as if
you if you can provide scientific
evidence that would be great. Um but do
we have agreement on MTP and uh APF?
If you um agree with adopting MTP and
APF, can you please raise your hand and
Surely
there are nine hands up
and then uh
all right so with nine hands up then we
have the adoption of MTP and APF. Those
frameworks will allow us to still create
those dosage levels. Um I admitted to
the first uh
I admitted the first time that
the dosage levels that I provided were
not final. Um but I did want to at least
say have something that way when you
guys are presenting your dosage levels
um and sending them to that email, we
can have something to base off of some
unifying factor to create the system as
a whole. I do think that the dosage
levels need a little more work. Um,
so I am totally open for comment.
>> And uh, Chris,
>> wait, before we jump to Chris, just to
let everybody know, we had to lower
everybody's hand because we [snorts]
couldn't tell if it was vote or if you
had comment. So, if you did have your
hand up and it was for comment, please
go on ahead and put it back on up. if it
was just because the vote and it was
still remnant hand uh being raised,
don't worry about that. But anyway, all
right, Chris,
two things like u we just voted four. We
didn't have a vote for those who were
against and can we vote on those two
things separately because I think there
may be some people that
uh would like the MTP but
uh not the not the AF APF.
Okay. Um
so let's just go ahead and read the vote
one more time. Please lower your hands
now.
If you would like to vote in the
affirmative of adopting MTP and APF
jointly, please raise your hand.
>> Okay, we have 10 hands raised at this
time. Any other?
>> All right, please lower your hands.
All right. Are all hands lowered? Not
yet.
>> We're working on that. Give us just a
>> perfect. Thank you.
[clears throat]
All right. If you would like to vote
against
the MTP and APF jointly, please raise
your hand.
>> We have one hand
>> with 10 in favor and one in objection.
The motion is passed. MTP and APF
definitions are adopted
for this. Um, now we can go ahead and do
the work of setting up the dosage
levels. I do want to give time for the
public to come up with those things. Uh,
um, so I will, if there is no other
comment, I will close the meeting, but I
did see a hand come up at the last
second. Gregory,
>> Greg, your mic has been enabled.
Um, [clears throat] we can deal with
this in another meeting, but I really
would have liked I asked to comment
before the vote. I feel like I should
have been given an opportunity to
comment before the vote and I feel very
strongly about this issue. I think that
I'm not against what we're measuring.
I'm trying to influence the acronym.
There is there is existing usage of PCN
to refer to the exact same thing with
the exact same calculations that you
have set.
I feel that PCN is a better term. And
then for psilocybin equivalency, PBCE
would be the correct term
that I just got to say that I think that
adopting the language
of MTP is not the right move.
>> Okay. Well, I appreciate your comment on
semantics. Um but if there are no other
discussion is everyone good to adjurnn?
>> Uh the only thing Ian uh the next
meeting
>> Oh yes yes yes. I'm so sorry guys. Um is
everyone okay with just push keeping the
schedule another two weeks
would be actually hold on next two weeks
would be the 13th. Um February 13th work
for everyone?
Raise your hand if you're good with the
13th.
Dominic, were we trying to hold off on f
further meetings until after session
concludes?
>> Yeah. Yes. And that's what Thank you,
Kathy. I was just checking on the
calendar. Um, we are asking right now,
Ian, for the committees to just hold off
until that point. Um, and uh, session
ends on the 19th. We do already have end
of life care on the 20th, but there are
uh and the the um board meets on the
27th on those Fridays. Um but uh either
on the Oh, I'm sorry, my calendar just
decided to skip into April. Uh but on
the 20th there is 3 to 5 is open at the
moment, February 20th. And then on the
27th, the afternoon is completely open
as far as committee meetings.
>> All righty. So, would you guys be okay
with 100 p.m. on the 27th?
>> Raise your hand if you would are good
with that.
>> And there's six hands at the moment.
Seven.
>> Seven hands.
>> Okay.
>> Six hands. and then or seven
six. Okay. Um
>> well, some people had lowered their
hands, so I think we ended up with about
eight or nine total.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> So then we will do the 27th at one. I
look forward to seeing you all there.
>> And please submit any public comments by
email by uh February 2nd, please. and
also your um dosage level
recommendations. Thank you guys.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh, can I also add um uh for submitting
comments for this committee, if you
could just indicate um specifically that
it's for this committee, the dosage
administration and clinical practice.
>> Yes.
All righty. Thank you guys. Have a great
rest of your day.
>> Thank you everybody.
[snorts]